很久以前 在一个遥远的银河系
A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away…
行星拉穆
PLANET LAH'MU
妈妈我们知道
Mama. We know.
琴 收好东西 是时候了
Jyn, gather your things, it's time.
你好
Hello.
索 我是莱拉
Saw, it's Lyra.
出事了
It's happened.
他来抓我们了
He's come for us.
你知怎么做
You know what to do.
琴 过来
Jyn, come here.
记住 无论我做啥
Remember, whatever I do,
我做它只为保护你
I do it to protect you.
说你懂
Say you understand.
我懂
I understand.
我爱你 星尘我爱你 爸爸
I love you, Stardust. I love you too, Papa.
盖伦
Galen.
走
Go.
琴
Jyn.
你知道去哪儿 是吧?
You know where to go, don't you?
相信原力
Trust the force.
你是个难找的人 盖伦但是务农?
You're a hard man to find, Galen. But farming?
真的 一个你之才能者?
Really, a man of your talents?
这是种平静的生活
It's a peaceful life.
也是孤独的 我猜想
It's lonely, I imagine.
自从莱拉死后 确实
Since Lyra died, yes.
噢
Oh.
哦
深感同情
My condolences.
搜搜屋子!
Search the house!
遵命
Understood.
你想怎样?
What is it you want?
工程已停滞 我需要你回来
The work has stalled, I need you to come back.
恕难从命 克伦尼克
I won't do it, Krennic.
我们正处伟大的边缘我们是如此之近于
We're on the verge of greatness. We were this close
提供和平 安全给银河系
to providing peace, security for the galaxy.
你在混淆和平与恐怖
You're confusing peace with terror.
是吗?
Well?
你总得重新开始
You have to start somewhere.
我会毫无用处 克伦尼克
I'll be of no help, Krennic.
我介意的只是它并非如此
My mind just isn't what it was.
想起你我就不爽
I have trouble remembering of you,
哪怕极简之事
even simple things.
盖伦
Galen,
你是一个有灵气的科学家 然而你是一个可怕的骗子
you're an inspired scientist but you're a terrible liar.
现在我想要挽回 我真如此
Now I admire the effort, I really do.
噢 看啦 莱拉死而复生 真是一个奇迹
Oh look, here's Lyra back from the dead. It's a miracle.
站住!
Stop!
噢 莱拉烦人依旧
Oh, Lyra. Troublesome as ever.
你不能带走他
You're not taking him.
行 当然我不能你们我都要带走
No, of course I'm not. I'm taking you all.
你们都要来你 你的孩子
You'll all come. You, your child,
你们都将生活安逸作为人质?
You'Ll all live in comfort. As hostages?
作为"帝国的英雄"
As 'heroes of the Empire. '
莱拉
Lyra.
放下它
Put it down.
想想 很仔细地
Think very carefully.
你毫无胜算动手
You will never win. Do it.
莱拉!
Lyra!
不!
No!
他们有个孩子
They have a child.
找到它!
Find it!
我的孩子
My child.
来
Come.
我们还有个漫长的旅程在我们前方
We have a long ride ahead of us.
星球大战外传：侠盗一号
检查 安全牢房区 4227
Check in, security. Cell block 4227
卡夫林环 贸易前哨
RING OF KAFRENE TRADING OUTPOST
我差点走了我尽快赶来的
I was about to leave. I came as fast as I could.
我必须回飞船上去
I have to get back on board.
跟我来返回杰达?
Walk with me. Back to Jedha?
他们会不等我就走!
They'll leave without me!
放松你有杰达的消息?快点
Easy. You have news from Jedha? Come on.
一个帝国飞行员 一个货运驾驶员他昨天叛逃了
An Imperial pilot, one of the cargo drivers. He defected yesterday.
他向人们宣告 帝国正在制造武器
He's telling people they're making a weapon.
凯伯晶体 那就是帝国想要的
The kyber crystals, that's what they're for.
什么类型的武器?
What kind of weapon?
行了 我得走了什么类型的武器?
Look, I have to go. What kind of weapon?
行星级杀手这就是他所说的
A planet killer. That's what he called it.
行星级杀手?
A planet killer?
一个叫厄索的人派他来
Someone named Erso sent him.
索的某个老朋友盖伦·厄索?
Some old friend of Saw's. Galen Erso?
是他?我可不知!我们离开时他们正在找索
Was it? I don't know! They were looking for Saw when we left.
还有谁知道这些?我不知道!
Who else knows this? I have no idea!
全都四分五裂了
It's all falling apart.
索是对的 间谍无处不在
Saw's right, there're spies everywhere
这是怎么回事?
What's all this?
快点 让我们看看证件
Come on, let's see some scandocs.
好啊 当然行我的手套?
Yeah, of course. My gloves?
不…
No…
你干了什么?
What've you done?
士兵增援 9区
Troopers down, section 9.
你疯了吗?
Are you crazy?
我爬不出这儿我的胳膊…
I'll never climb out of here. My arm. . .
别挡道让开! 让开!
Get out of the way. Move! Move!
冷静下冷静下
Calm down. Calm down.
我们会没事的
We'll be all right.
杰达 帝国占领伴星
JEDHA IMPERIAL-OCCUPIED MOON
长官
Sir.
那是他吗?
Is that him?
他看起来与众不同
He looks kind of different
超乎我的想象
than I imagined.
在你脚下!
On your feet!
是飞行员…那个叛逃者
It's the pilot…the defector.
好的 那 你是-你是索·格雷拉?
Okay, so you're-you're Saw Gerrera?
索·格雷拉不是?
Saw Gerrera. No?
好吧 我们这是在浪费不该浪费的时间
Okay, we're just wasting time that we don't have.
我需要跟索·格雷拉谈!我之前不断跟他们说 趁还不迟
I need to speak to Saw Gerrera! I keep telling them before, before it's too late.
低下你的头!
Keep your heads down!
帝国兵将搜捕他…
The Imperials will be searching for him. . .
我们要离开这不毛之地我们必须去杰达之城
We're out here in the middle of nowhere. We need to get to Jedha City.
紧急消息的哪部分你们这些家伙有不明白的吗?
What part of urgent message do you guys not understand?
嘿!
Hey!
我们都是站一边的 只要你多看这身制服一分钟…
We'Re all on the same side, If you just see past the uniform for a minute…
我得跟啊…我得跟索·格雷拉谈谈
I've got to speak to ah…I've got to speak to Saw Gerrera.
沃巴尼
WOBANI
帝国劳改营
IMPRIAL LABOR CAMP
什么事?
What now?
不知道肯定是再上一个
I don't know. Must be another pick up.
我以为都在这
I thought we had everybody.
全部消灭 长官哈妮可!
All clear, sir. Hallik!
利安娜·哈妮可!她
Liana Hallik!Her.
你想离开这儿吗?
You want to get out of here?
嘿!那我呢?
Hey! What about me?
恭喜你得救了
Congratulations. You are being rescued
请不要抵抗
Please do not resist.
雅文四号
YAVIN 4
反抗军联盟总部
REBEL ALLIANCE HEADQUARTERS
LU-28, 向四级维修汇报
LU-28, report to maintenance level 4.
你现在自称利安娜·哈妮可对吗?
You're currently calling yourself Liana Hallik. Is that correct?
持有未经批准的武器 伪造皇家文件
Possession of unsanctioned weapons, forgery of Imperial documents,
严重伤害 越狱 拒捕…
Aggravated assault, Escape from custody, Resisting arrest…
试想下如果帝国当局发现你真的是谁琴·厄索?
Imagine if the Imperial authorities had found out who you really were. Jyn Erso?
这是你的本名 不是吗?
That's your given name, is it not?
琴·厄索?盖伦·厄索之女
Jyn Erso? Daughter of Galen Erso.
一位知名的帝国武器开发合作者
A known Imperial collaborator in weapons development.
这算什么?
What is this?
有个机会能让你重新开始
It's a chance for you to make a fresh start.
我们认为你可能会帮助我们
We think you might be able to help us.
他是卡西安·安多上尉 反抗军情报员
This is Captain Cassian Andor, Rebel Intelligence.
你最后一次联系父亲是什么时候?
When was the last time you were in contact with your father?
15年前
15 years ago.
可知那些时候他身在何处?
Any idea where he's been all that time?
我常常想他是死了 让事情更简单
I like to think he's dead, makes things easier.
比什么简单?他被当成一个帝国战争机器的工具?
Easier than what? That he's being a tool of the Imperial war machine?
我对各种政见从未有过奢望真的?
I've never had the luxury of political opinions. Really?
你最后一次联系索·格雷拉是什么时候?
When was your last contact with Saw Gerrera?
那已有很长一段时间
It's been a long time.
他还记得你 还是 忘了?
He'd remember you, though, wouldn't he?
他可能同意见你 如果你作为朋友去
He might agree to meet you, if you came as a friend.
我们在此分秒必争 孩子 如果没啥可谈
We're up against the clock here, girl, So if there's nothing to talk about
我们只需把你送还原处
we'll just put you back where we found you.
我还是小孩时 索·格雷拉救过我的命
I was a child, Saw Gerrera saved my life.
他救出我 但是我不知他在哪儿我有些年没看到他了
He raised me. But I've no idea where he is. I haven't seen him in years.
我们知道怎么找到他 那不是我们的问题
We know how to find him, that's not our problem.
我们需要的是一个带我们入门而不被杀掉的人
What we need is someone who gets us through the door without being killed.
你们都是反抗军 是吗?
You're all rebels, aren't you?
是的 但索·格雷拉是一个极端分子
Yes, but Saw Gerrera's an extremist.
他一直都在为自己战斗从他脱离了反抗军以来
He's been fighting on his own since he broke with the Rebellion.
他的战斗给联盟带来了很多问题
His militancy has caused the Alliance a great many problems.
我们别无选择 只得尝试修复打破的信任
We have no choice now but to try to mend that broken trust.
这跟我父亲又有什么关系?
What does this have to do with my father?
有个帝国反叛者在杰达一个飞行员
There's an Imperial defector in Jedha. A pilot.
他被索·格雷拉绑架
He's being held by Saw Gerrera.
他声称皇帝正在制造一个有能力摧毁整个行星的武器
He's claiming the Emperor is creating a weapon with the power to destroy entire planets.
飞行员说他是受你父亲派遣
The pilot says he was sent by your father.
我们需要在武器完成前阻止它
We need to stop this weapon before it is finished.
安多上尉的任务是证实飞行员的故事 之后 如有可能 找到你父亲
Captain Andor's mission is to authenticate the pilot's story and then, if possible, find your father.
看来他对这个超级武器的开发至关重要
It appears he is critical to the development of this superweapon.
考虑到情况的严重性及你跟索的渊源
Given the gravity of the situation and your history with Saw,
我们希望他能帮我们找到你父亲再让他返回参议院作证
we're hoping that he will help us locate your father and return him to the Senate for testimony.
如果我做了?
And if I do it?
我们会确保你自由
We'll make sure you go free.
安多上尉!
Captain Andor!
我是克图偶
I'm Kay-Tuesso (K-2SO)
我是一个重编程帝国机器人
I'm a reprogrammed Imperial droid.
我记得你
I remember you.
我看委员会是派你跟我们一起去杰达
I see the Council is sending you with us to Jedha.
很显然
Apparently so.
这是个坏主意
That is a bad idea.
我认为是 卡西安也认为是
I think so, and so does Cassian.
我怎么知道?我的专业就是战略分析
What do I know? My specialty is just strategic analysis.
盖伦·厄索对帝国的武器计划至关重要
Galen Erso is vital to the Empire's weapon program.
忘记你在那里听到的 不用汇报
Forget what you heard in there, there will be no extraction.
你找到他 你杀了他
You find him You kill him.
然后又当场
Then and there.
你见过克图了?
You met Kay-Tu?
迷人
Charming.
他倾向于电脑里冒出啥就说啥
He tends to say whatever comes into his circuits.
这是重编程的副产品
It's a by-product of the reprogram.
为什么她有冲击波而我没有?
Why does she get a blaster, and I don't?
什么?我知道怎么用
What. I know how to use it.
那正是我所担心的 把它给我
That's what I'm afraid of. Give it to me.
我们要去杰达那可是战区
We're going to Jedha. That's a war zone.
这不是重点
That's not the point.
你哪里拿的?我找到的
Where did you get it?I found it.
我发现这回复含糊且不可信
I find that answer vague and unconvincing.
信任是互相的
Trust goes both ways.
你就让她留着它?
You're letting her keep it?
你想知道她用它对付你的概率吗?
Would you like to know the probability of her using it against you?
很高让我们出发吧
It's high. Let's get going.
非常高
It's very high.
谎言!
Lies!
欺骗!
Deceptions!
让我们看看
Let's see it.
菩提·鲁克货物飞行员
Bodhi Rook. Cargo pilot.
本地人 呵呵?嗯-哼
Local boy, huh? Uh-huh.
这是从他的靴子里找到的 当他被抓到的时候
This was found in his boot when he was captured.
好的 我能听见你
Okay, I can hear you.
他没有抓住我 我自己来的
He didn't capture me, I came here myself.
我叛逃 我叛逃
I defected, I defected.
每一天 更多谎言
Every day, more lies.
谎言?
Lies?
我会为谎言不顾一切?不 我们没时间这样!
Would I risk everything for a lie? No, we don't have time for this!
我得跟索·格雷拉谈谈 在一切太迟之前
I have to speak to Saw Gerrera before it's too late.
好吧…
Okay. . .
那 你…
So, you. . .
呃.
Um.
哦. 那个-那个是给你的
Uh. That's-That's for you.
而我把它给他们 他们却没发现
And I gave it to them, they did not find it!
我把它给他们
I gave it to them.
盖伦·厄索
Galen Erso.
他叫我找你
He told me to find you.
博尔·格莱特
Bor Gullet.
博尔·格莱特?
Bor Gullet?
什么？等等！
What? Wait!
盖伦·厄索派我来!
Galen Erso sent me!
他叫我找到你!
He told me to find you!
最不幸的是杰达的安全漏洞 主管克伦尼克
Most unfortunate about the security breach on Jedha, Director Krennic.
经过这么多的挫折和延误 现在又这样
After so many setbacks and delays, and now this.
我们听到谣言在城里流传
We've heard word of rumors circulating through the city.
显然你失去了一位相当健谈的货运飞行员
Apparently you've lost a rather talkative cargo pilot.
如果参议院得到我们项目的风声 无数的系统将集结于反抗军
If the Senate gets wind of our project, countless systems will flock to the Rebellion.
一旦战斗空间站完工 总督塔金 参议院就会很少关注
When the battle station is finished, Governor Tarkin, the Senate will be of little concern.
一旦已成现在 主管克伦尼克皇帝决不容许再拖延
When has become now, Director Krennic. The Emperor will tolerate no further delay,
你已让时间成为反抗军的盟友
you have made time an ally of the Rebellion.
我建议 我们同时解决这两个问题 通过直接测试武器
I suggest, we solve both problems simultaneously with an immediate test of the weapon.
失败将会找到你要一个耐心不足的观众的原因
Failure will find you explaining why to a far less patient audience.
我不会失败
I will not fail.
怎么了 琴?你看起来很害怕
What's the matter, Jyn? You looked frightened.
我会永远保护你
I'll always protect you.
星尘
Stardust.
永远不会改变
Don't ever change.
相信…
Trust. . .
盖伦
Galen.
我们即将进入轨道你来操控
We're coming into orbit. You have controls.
那就是杰达
That's Jedha.
它还剩下些什么
Or what's left of it.
我们要找索 我们要找你父亲
We find Saw, we find your father.
驱逐舰在这里干什么?
What's with the Destroyer?
这都是因为你的老朋友 索·格雷拉
It's because of your old friend, Saw Gerrera.
他一直在袭击货物运输
He's been attacking the cargo shipments.
他们带什么来了?
What are they bringing in?
其实是"他们带什么走了"?
It's 'what are they taking out?'
凯伯水晶所有能带走的
Kyber crystal. All they can get.
我们想知其为何拆圣殿 现在知道了
We wondered why they were stripping the temple, now we know.
那是武器的燃料
It's the fuel for the weapon.
你父亲建造的武器
The weapon your father's building.
也许我们应该把靶子留下
Maybe we should leave target practice behind.
你在说我吗?
Are you talking about me?
她说得对
She's right.
我们要混进去留在飞船里
We need to blend in. Stay with the ship.
我可以混进去我是帝国机器人
I can blend in. I'm an Imperial droid.
此城被帝国占领
This city is under Imperial occupation
这里半数人想把你重新编程另一半想在你的头上打个洞
Half the people here want to reprogram you. The other half want to put a hole in your head.
我很惊讶你是如此关心我的安全
I'm surprised you're so concerned with my safety.
我可没有 我只是担心他们可能惦记你而打我
I'm not. I'm just worried they might miss you and hit me.
听起来对我不算太坏
Doesn't sound so bad to me.
博尔·格莱特能感觉到你的想法
Bor Gullet can feel your thoughts,
没有谎言就安全
No lie is safe.
你给我真正带了什么 货运飞行员?
What have you really brought me, cargo pilot?
博尔·格莱特会知道真象
Bor Gullet will know the truth.
令人遗憾的副作用
The unfortunate side effect,
就是人们常常失去自己的意识不
is that one tends to lose one's mind. No.
嘿 你要看好自己?
Hey, you just watch yourself.
不好意思观光者 我们不想惹任何麻烦 抱歉
No, no. Tourist, we don't want any trouble, sorry.
来吧来吧
Come on. Come on.
杰达的公民
Citizens of Jedha,
你必须上报失踪的货运飞行员的位置信息
you must come forward with information of the location of this missing cargo pilot.
此信息的600学分奖励即可授予
A reward of 600 credits for the information shall be awarded.
我有个联络人 索的反抗军之一
I had a contact, one of Saw's rebels,
但是他已失踪了他的妹妹在找他
but he's just gone missing. His sister will be looking for him.
圣殿被摧毁了但她会在那里等着
The temple's been destroyed but she'll be there waiting.
我们会给她你的名字 希望这样能让我们见索
We'll give her your name and hope that gets us a meeting with Saw.
希望?
Hope?
对反抗就是基于希望
Yeah. Rebellions are built on hope.
把手放到我看得见的地方去哪边
Hands where I can see them. Get over there.
出示证件进去搜
Show me some identification. Check inside.
这一切都因为你那飞行员?
Is this all because of your pilot?
愿他人的原力与你同在
May the Force of others be with you.
愿他人的原力与你同在等着我
May the Force of others be with you. Wait for me.
愿他人的原力与你同在
May the Force of others be with you.
你愿意交易那条项链以窥见你的未来吗?
Would you trade that necklace for a glimpse into your future?
是的 我是跟你说
Yes, I'm speaking to you.
我是奇鲁·英威
I am Chirrut Îmwe.
你怎么知道我戴着项链?
How did you know I was wearing a necklace?
想知道答案你必须付钱
For that answer you must pay.
凯伯水晶你知道些啥?
What do you know of kyber crystals?
我父亲 他说它们提供能源给绝地的光剑
My father, he said they powered the Jedi lightsabers.
琴来吧 我们走
Jyn. Come on, let's go.
最强的星星都有凯伯之心
The strongest stars have hearts of kyber.
我们走
Let's go.
我们不是来交朋友的
We're not here to make friends.
他们是谁?
Who are they?
威尔人护卫队
The Guardians of the Whills.
凯伯圣殿的保护者
Protectors of the Kyber Temple.
但没有什么可以保护 所以现在他们只是给大家造成麻烦
But there's nothing left to protect, so now they're just causing trouble for everybody.
你突然变得非常紧张
You seem awfully tense all of a sudden.
我们必须快点这儿-将有伏击
We have to hurry. This town-It's ready to blow.
帝国的公民们
Citizens of the Empire,
帝国军队不懈的战斗...索的反抗军给这座心爱的城市的居民带来恐怖...
Imperial forces tirelessly fight.Saw Gerrera's reign of terror...
真相和正义就是帝国的武器
Truth and justice are the tools of the Empire.
告诉我你有后备计划
Tell me you have a backup plan.
来了
Incoming.
放下武器
Put your guns down.
我们后面
Behind us.
看起来我们已找到索的反抗军了
Looks like we found Saw's rebels.
琴 别!
Jyn, no!
谢谢你
Thank you.
打掉高塔
Hit the tower.
离开那儿!
Get out of there!
快点啊 凯伯水晶 拿它
Quickly, the kyber, get it.
这里 取走凯伯水晶
Here, take the kyber.
取走凯伯水晶
Take the kyber.
来吧!
Come on!
这边!
This way!
你知道那不是我?
Did you know that wasn't me?
那是当然!
Of course!
我想我告诉过你呆在飞船里
I thought I told you to stay on the ship
你说过 但我觉得无聊 何况你们有麻烦
You did, but I thought it was boring, and you were in trouble.
对两个混入者来说爆炸似乎太多了
There are a lot of explosions for two people blending in.
呆那儿别动…
Freeze right there. . .
你是对的 我应该在飞船里等着
You're right, I should just wait on the ship.
站住!站在那儿!
Halt! Stop right there!
你带这些囚犯去哪里?
Where are you taking these prisoners?
他们是囚犯是的你带他们去哪儿?
These are prisoners. Yes. Where are you taking them?
我要带他们…关押他们在监狱里
I am taking them…to imprison them. In prison.
他带我们去…安静!
He's taking us to…Quiet!
再来个新鲜的如果你又张嘴!
And there's a fresh one if you mouth off again!
我们需在此看住他们那也行
We'll take them from here. That's okay.
如果你能指正我的方向 我带他们走 我能行
If you could just point me in the right direction, I can take them, I'm sure.
我已带他们走了这么远— 嘿 稍等一会儿
I'Ve taken them this far—Hey, Wait a second.
带走他们等等!嘿 机器人
Take them away. Wait!Hey, droid.
你不能带走他们!
You can't take them away!
你留在这儿我们需要检查你的诊断程序
You stay here. We need to check your diagnostics.
诊断程序?
Diagnostics?
我能够运行我自己的诊断程序 非常感谢你
I'm capable of running my own diagnostics, thank you very much.
让他们和平地过去!
Let them pass in peace!
Let them pass in peace.
原力与我同在我与原力同在
The Force is with me, and I am with the Force.
而我无所畏惧 因一切皆为原力所愿
And I fear nothing, for all is as the Force wills it.
嘿!站那儿!
Hey!Stop right there!
他是盲人
He's blind.
他聋了吗?我说了：站那儿!
Is he deaf? I said: Stop right there!
你的脚还好吧?
Is your foot all right?
你差点射中我
You almost shot me.
你太客气了
You're welcome.
敌兵清除!
Clear of hostiles!
一个敌兵!他和我们一起!
One hostile!He's with us!
他们没事
They're all right.
谢谢了
Thanks.
卡西安 那巴掌我很抱歉
Cassian, I'm sorry about the slap.
回到飞船上去等我叫你
Go back to the ship. Wait for my call.
他是绝地?
Is he a Jedi?
这里再也没有绝地了
There are no Jedi here anymore.
只有这种傻样梦想家
Only dreamers like this fool.
原力保护了我
The Force did protect me.
我保护着你
I protected you.
你能带我们去见索·格雷拉吗?
Can you get us to Saw Gerrera?
难道你看不出我们不是帝国的朋友吗?
Can't you see we are no friends of the Empire?
跟那个杀了我们的人的家伙说去
Tell that to the one who killed our men.
任何杀掉我或我朋友的人将会被索·格雷拉问责
Anyone who kills me or my friends will answer to Saw Gerrera.
那是为何?
And why is that?
因为我是盖伦·厄索之女
Because I am the daughter of Galen Erso.
带他们走!
Take them!
你在耍我吧?我是盲人!
Are you kidding me? I'm blind!
我与原力同在 原力与我同在
I'm one with the Force and the Force is with me.
求神?
You pray?
我与原力同在 原力与我同在
I'm one with the Force and the Force is with me.
真的?
Really?
我与原力同在 原力与我同在
I'm one with the Force and the Force is with me.
他在求神开门
He's praying for the door to open.
这会困扰他 因为他知道这是可能的
It bothers him, because he knows it is possible.
贝兹·马彪斯曾是我们中最忠实的守护者
Baze Malbus was once the most devoted Guardian of us all.
我开始觉得原力跟我有不同的优先权
I'm beginning to think the Force and I have different priorities.
放松些 上尉我们呆过比这更糟糕的笼子
Relax, Captain. We've been in worse cages than this one.
这可是我头一遭
This is a first for me.
还有另一种监狱 上尉
There is more than one sort of prison, Captain,
我感觉你无论身在何处都带着它
I sense that you carry yours wherever you go.
琴
Jyn.
真的是你?
Is it really you?
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
真是相当惊喜
Must be quite a surprise.
我们仍是朋友?
Are we not still friends?
最后一次我见你 你给我一把刀和上膛的冲击波
The last time I saw you, you gave me a knife and loaded blaster
还叫我呆在地堡里直到天亮
and told me to wait in a bunker until daylight.
我知道你很安全
I knew you were safe.
你丢下我
You left me behind.
你已成为我骨干中最好的士兵
You were already the best soldier in my cadre.
我才16岁我在保护你!
I was sixteen. I was protecting you!
你扔下我!
You dumped me!
你是帝国的科学官员的女儿!
You were the daughter of an Imperial science officer!
人们总会想得出来
People were starting to figure that out.
人们会想要-拿你当人质
People who wanted to-to use you as a hostage.
没有哪天逝去而我却不想你…
Not a day goes by that I don'T think of you…
但是今天 所有的日子?
But today, of all days?
这是个陷阱 不是吗?
It's a trap, isn't it?
什么?
What?
那飞行员!
The pilot!
消息所有这些
The message. All of it.
是他们…
Did they. . .
派你来?
send you?
你来这里只为杀我?
Did you come here to kill me?
我时日不多
There's not much of me left.
联盟想要我父亲
The Alliance wants my father.
他们认为他有给过你一个武器的消息
They think he's sent you a message about a weapon.
我猜他们想派我来而你可能就愿意帮他们一把
I guess they think by sending me you might actually help them out.
那你想要的又是什么 琴?
So what is it that you want, Jyn?
他们想要个介绍人 他们如愿了
They wanted an introduction, they've got it.
我现在退出你接下来想干啥就干啥
I'm out now. The rest of you can do what you want.
你不关心原因?
You care not about the cause?
原因?
The cause?
严肃地?
Seriously?
联盟?
The Alliance?
The. . .
反抗军?不管它是啥 那些日子你以此为名?
The rebels? Whatever it is you're calling yourself these days?
所有这些带给我只是痛苦
All it's ever brought me is pain.
你能袖手旁观帝国的旗帜插满银河系?
You can stand to see the Imperial flag reign across the galaxy?
这不是问题 如果你不仰望
It's not a problem if you don't look up.
我有点东西给你看
I have something to show you,
来
come.
皇帝在等着我的汇报
The Emperor is awaiting my report.
他曾希望和勋爵维达于此共赏难得盛况
One had hoped that he and Lord Vader might have been here for such an occasion.
而我认为此举可谨慎地拯救你于任何潜在的尴尬中
And I thought it prudent to save you from any potential embarrassment.
你的担忧完全没必要
Your concern is hardly warranted.
说到就要做到
If saying it would only make it so.
所有帝国军队都撤离了 我就会摧毁整个伴星
All Imperial forces, have been evacuated, and I stand ready to destroy the entire moon.
那不是必须的我们需要一个声明 而非一个宣言
That won't be necessary. We need a statement, not a manifesto.
对这天来说 圣城已经足够
The Holy City will be enough for the day.
目标杰达之城 准备单核反应堆点火
Target Jedha City, prepare single reactor ignition.
长官 我们已就位 准备好…发射!
Sir, we're in position, ready to…Fire!
开始第一次点火
Commence primary ignition.
隔壁牢房的是谁?
Who's the one in the next cell?
什么?
What?
哪里?
Where?
一个帝国飞行员
An Imperial pilot.
飞行员?我要杀了基姆!
Pilot? I'm going to kill Kim!
别 别 别 等等!来这儿!
No, no, No, wait!Come here!
不!
NO!
退后退后
Back off. Back off.
好吧
Okay.
你是飞行员?
Are you the pilot?
嘿 嘿—你是飞行员?太空飞行员?
Hey, Hey—Are you the pilot?The shuttle pilot?
飞行员?
Pilot?
他这是怎么了?
What's wrong with him?
盖伦·厄索
Galen Erso.
你知那个名字?
You know that name?
我带了信息 我是飞行员
I brought the message, I'm the pilot.
我是飞行员
I'm the pilot.
行了 好的
Okay, good.
现在盖伦·厄索在哪儿?
Now where is Galen Erso?
待命
Standby.
这是我收到的消息
This is the message I was sent.
索 如果你正在看这个
Saw, if you're watching this,
那么也许就有机会拯救联盟
then perhaps there is a chance to save the Alliance.
也许有一个机会来解释我自己 虽然我不敢奢望太多
Perhaps there's a chance to explain myself and, though I don't dare hope for too much,
一个给琴的机会 如果她还活着
a chance for Jyn, if she's alive,
如果你有可能找到她…
If you can possibly find her…
让她知道
to let her know that
我对她的爱从未褪色 我是多么强烈地想念她
my love for her has never faded and how desperately I've missed her.
琴 我的星尘
Jyn, my Stardust,
我无法料想你对我的想法
I can't imagine what you think of me.
当我被带走时 我得面对那些痛苦事实
When I was taken, I faced some bitter truths.
我被告知 很快 克伦尼克也会抓到你
I was told that, soon enough, Krennic would have you as well.
随着时间的推移 我知道你要么死了
As time went by, I knew that you were either dead
要么隐藏得如此好 他永远找不到你
or so well hidden that he would never find you.
我知道如果我拒绝工作
I knew if I refused to work,
如果我夺走我自己的生命 那只是一个时间问题
if I took my own life, it would only be a matter of time
在克伦尼克意识到他不再需要我去完成项目之前
before Krennic realized he no longer needed me to complete the project.
所以我做了一件没人期望的事：我撒谎了
So I did the one thing that nobody expected: I lied.
我学会了撒谎
I learned to lie.
我扮演成被挫败的借工作逃避的人的一员
I played the part of a beaten man resigned to the sanctuary of his work.
我让自己不可缺少
I made myself indispensable,
我一直在打造我的复仇基础
and all the while I laid the groundwork of my revenge.
我们称之为死星
We call it the Death Star.
没有更好的名称
There is no better name.
而这一天必将很快来到 一旦它被释放
And the day is coming soon when it will be unleashed.
我已在系统里面设置了一个弱点
I've placed a weakness deep within the system.
一个如此小而强大的缺陷 他们永远也找不到
A flaw so small and powerful, they'll never find it.
但 琴琴 如果你正在听…
Jyn, If you'Re listening…But, Jyn.
我的爱女 我的生命有如此之多已被浪费
My beloved, so much of my life has been wasted.
只有在我坚强的时刻 我才尽力想你
I try to think of you only in the moments when I'm strong,
因为那些没有你在我身边的痛苦…
Because the pain of not having you with me…
你的母亲
Your mother.
我们一家人
Our family.
这些失去的痛苦是如此压倒一切 即使现在我也可能失败
The pain of that loss is so overwhelming I risk failing even now.
这是如此之难如不想你
It's just so hard not to think of you.
想着你在哪里
Think of where you are.
我的星尘
My Stardust.
索 反应堆模块 这是关键
Saw, the reactor module, that's the key.
那是我埋设机关的地方
That's the place I've laid my trap.
它很隐蔽且不稳定
It's well hidden and unstable,
击中它的任何部分都会摧毁整个空间站
one blast to any part of it will destroy the entire station.
你需要蓝图
You'll need the plans,
死星的结构蓝图以找到反应堆
the structural plans for the Death Star to find the reactor.
我知道有一个完整的工程档案存于数据库中
I know there's a complete engineering archive in the data vault
位于斯卡里夫的堡垒之塔
at the Citadel Tower on Scarif.
任何增压爆炸都能使反应堆模块点燃
Any pressurized explosion to the reactor module will set off
连锁反应就会摧毁整个空间站…
a chain reaction that will destroy the entire station. . .
走走
Go. Go.
克图?克图 你在哪儿?
K-2? K-2, where are you?
你好啊
There you are.
我遵照你的要求正在候旨虽然地平线上有麻烦了
I'm standing by as you requested. Although there's a problem on the horizon.
地平线没了
There is no horizon.
锁定我们位置把飞船开过来 马上
Locate our position. Bring that ship in here now!
你去哪儿?
Where are you going?
我必须找到琴
I've got to find Jyn.
救飞行员我们需要他好的
Get the pilot. We need him. All right.
我去救飞行员
I'll get the pilot.
飞行员
Pilot.
别 别 别
No, no, no.
我们走
Let's go.
琴!
Jyn!
我们必须走了
We've got to go.
我知道你父亲在哪儿
I know where your father is.
跟着他 琴
Go with him, Jyn.
你必须去
You must go.
一起来我不再落跑了
Come with us. I will run no longer.
来吧但你必须救自己
Come on. But you must save yourself.
来吧走!
Come on. Go!
没时间了!
There's no time!
拯救反抗军!
Save the Rebellion!
拯救梦想!
Save the dream!
噢真是漂亮
Oh. It's beautiful.
奇鲁 我们走!
Chirrut, let's go!
快点!让我们离开这儿!
Come on! Let's get out of here!
带我们离开这儿!冲出去!
Get us out of here! Punch it!
我对我们的处境并不乐观让我们都不 克
I'm not very optimistic about our role. Let's not, K
快点!
Come on!
冲出去我还没有完成我的计算
Punch it. I haven't completed my calculation.
我来帮你处理这些的
I'll make them for you.
我相信 我欠你一个道歉 主管克伦尼克
I believe I owe you an apology, Director Krennic.
你的工作超出了所有的期望
Your work exceeds all expectations.
你也会如此禀呈皇帝?
And you'll tell the Emperor as much?
我会禀呈他 他对你的意外事故的耐心已被回报以
I will tell him his patience with your misadventures has been rewarded
一个能迅速消灭反抗军的武器
with a weapon that will bring a swift end to the Rebellion.
那只是它的破坏潜力之一点—
That was only an inkling of it'S destructive potential—
我会禀呈他 我会接管控制这武器
I will tell him, that I will be taking control over the weapon
我几年前第一次说的话… 立即生效
I first spoke of years ago…Effective immediately.
我们站在这里之际 我的成就—不是你的!
We stand here amid my achievement—Not yours!
我担心最近的这些安全漏洞已经暴露了你作为一个军事总监的不足之处
I'm afraid these recent security breaches have laid bare your inadequacies as a military director.
漏洞已经补上
The breaches have been filled,
杰达已经沉寂
Jedha has been silenced.
你以为那个飞行员单独行动?
You think this pilot acted alone?
他是从伊杜的基地派出的
He was dispatched from the installation on Eadu.
盖伦·厄索的设施
Galen Erso's facility.
我们得去查查这个
We'll see about this.
一条加密信息来自安多上尉 长官
A coded message from Captain Andor, sir.
武器确认杰达被毁
Weapon confirmed. Jedha destroyed.
任务目标位于伊杜请指示
Mission target located on Eadu. Please advise.
被毁了?
Destroyed?
继续
Proceed.
告诉他我的命令仍然有效
Tell him my orders still stand.
告诉他行动要快 按计划行事
Tell him to proceed with haste and keep to the plan.
我们不知道他为帝国建造的是什么
We have no idea what he is building for the Empire.
我们必须杀掉盖伦·厄索 趁我们有机会
We have to kill Galen Erso while we have the chance.
贝兹 告诉我
Baze, tell me.
所有的?
All of it?
整个城市?
The whole city?
告诉我所有的
Tell me. All of it.
明白
Understood.
设置航线到伊杜
Set a course for Eadu.
Setting course for Eadu.
我父亲就在哪儿?
Is that where my father is?
我觉得是
I think so.
你就是盖伦的女儿
So you're Galen's daughter.
你认识他?
You know him?
我是菩提 飞行员
I'm Bodhi, the pilot.
你带了消息
You brought the message.
是的 你父亲…
Yes, your father. . .
他说我靠自己可以做好
He said I could get right by myself.
他说我可以做好 如果我足够勇敢
He said I could make it right, if I was brave enough
要倾听心中所想
and listened to what was in my heart.
为之行动
Do something about it.
估计来不及了
Guess it was too late.
还不算太迟
It wasn't too late.
似乎于我已相当晚了
Seems pretty late to me.
不
No.
我们可以打败那些坏事的人
We can beat the people who did this.
我父亲的消息 我已看过
My father's message, I've seen it.
他们称之为死星
They call it the Death Star.
但是他们不知道有方法可战胜它
But they have no idea there's a way to defeat it.
你们误解了我父亲
You're wrong about my father.
他确实建造了它因为他知他们仍会造好就算不靠他
He did build it. Because he knew they'd do it without him.
我的父亲做了一个选择
My father made a choice.
他为反抗军牺牲了自己
He sacrificed himself for the Rebellion.
他在里面埋设了一个机关
He's rigged a trap inside it
那就是他派你来的原因为带出这消息
That's why he sent you. To bring that message.
它在哪儿?
Where is it?
消息在哪儿?
Where's the message?
那是个全息影像
It was a hologram.
你有那消息 对吗?
You have that message, right?
所有的事发生得太快
Everything happened so fast.
你看过它?
Did you see it?
你不相信我
You don't believe me.
我可不是你要说服的人
I'm not the one you've got to convince.
我相信她
I believe her.
承蒙告知
That's good to know.
什么样的机关?
What kind of trap?
你说过你父亲造了个机关
You said your father made a trap.
反应堆
The reactor
他放置了一个弱点在那里他把它隐藏了很多年
He's placed a weakness there. He's been hiding it for years.
他说只要你能攻击反应堆-模块-整个系统就会崩溃
He said if you can blow the reactor-the modulethe whole system goes down.
你需要发消息给联盟
You need to send word to the Alliance.
我已经发了
I've done that.
他们必须知道有办法能摧毁这东西
They have to know there's a way to destroy this thing.
他们必须去斯卡里夫拿到蓝图我不能冒这个险
They have to go to Scarif to get the plans. I can't risk sending that.
我们在帝国势力范围的中心
We're in the heart of Imperial territory.
那么我们就要找到他再带他回来
Then we'll find him. And bring him back,
他就能亲自告诉他们
and he can tell them himself.
航线设往伊杜 长官
Course set for Eadu, sir.
伊杜 帝国凯伯水晶精炼厂
EADU IMPERIAL KYBER REFINERY
我与原力同在 原力与我同在
I'm one with the Force and the Force is with me.
二十度转右
20 egress to the right.
十度向上
10 degrees up.
不 不 不 低些低些!
No, no, no, lower. Lower!
你确定是这条路?
Are you sure this is the way?
他们有落地跟踪器他们有巡逻中队
They have landing trackers. They have patrol squadrons.
你必须穿行峡谷 保持低飞
You've got to stay in the canyon, keep it low.
注意你右侧!
Watch your right!
有百分之二十六的失败机率
There's a 26% chance of failure.
还有多远?
How much farther?
我不知道我不确定 我从未真的飞这条路
I don't know. I'm not sure, I never really come this way,
不过我们很近了 我们很近了我知道的
but we're close, we're close. I know that.
好了 现在有百分之三十五的失败机率我不想知道 谢谢你
Well, now there's a 35% chance of failure. I don't want to know, thank you.
我理解
I understand.
马上!马上停下!有风…
Now! Put it down now!The wind. . .
如果你继续走 你就会飞过穿梭机库右侧
If you keep going, you'll be right over the shuttle depot.
当心!嘿!
Watch out!Hey!
抓紧了!我们要强行着陆!
Hold on tight! We're coming down hard!
再试下在试 长官我们…
Try them again. I am, sir. We. . .
信号消失了
The signal's gone dead.
中队集合 目标伊杜
Squadron up, target Eadu.
现在如何?检查稳定装置?
How about now, check stabilizers?
菩提 实验室在哪儿?研究机构?
Bodhi, where's the lab? The research facility?
是啊 它在哪儿?
Yeah. Where is it?
它就在山脊上
It's just over the ridge.
我们正前方那个机库?你确定是它?
And that's a shuttle depot straight ahead of us? You are sure of that?
是的
Yes.
我们必须期望还有一艘帝国飞船留下可偷
We'll have to hope there's still an Imperial ship left to steal.
我们要这样去干
Here's what we're doing.
唯愿风暴继续 掩藏我们于此处
Hopefully, the storm keeps up and keeps us hidden down here.
菩提 你跟我来
Bodhi, you're coming with me.
我们爬上山脊看看
We'll go up the ridge and check it out.
我跟你去
I'm coming with you.
别 你父亲的消息 我们不能拿它冒险
No, your father's message, we can't risk it.
你是信使
You're the messenger.
真是可笑我们都得到了消息在此人人皆知
That's ridiculous. We all got the message. Everyone here knows it.
一发击中反应堆模块则整个系统垮掉
One blast to the reactor module and the whole system goes down.
这就是你说的整个系统垮掉
That's how you said it. The whole system goes down.
快去修我们的通讯器!
Get to work fixing our comms!
此刻我全部想做的就是掌控我们所要面对的问题
All I want to do right now is get a handle on what we're up against.
所以 我们要非常轻微且非常小心地到山脊上看看有些什么
So, we're going to go very small and very carefully up the rise and see what's what.
我们出去吧
Let's get out of here.
他看上去象个凶手?
Does he look like a killer?
不他有一张朋友脸
No. He has the face of a friend.
你在说谁?
Who are you talking about?
安多上尉
Captain Andor.
为什么你要问这个?你指什么 他看上去象个凶手?
Why do you ask that? What do you mean, does he look like a killer?
原力接近一个即将杀人的生物会变得黑暗
The Force moves darkly near a creature that's about to kill.
他的武器是狙击配置
His weapon was in the sniper configuration.
别 别 别…我们必须上去
No, no, no…We got to go up.
在那下面你看不到太多
You can't see much from down there.
走这边
This way.
我会跟着你的
I'll be right behind you.
来吧
Come on.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
我要跟着琴她的路很清晰
I'm going to follow Jyn. Her path is clear.
一个人?祝好运!
Alone? Good luck!
我不需要好运 我有你!
I don't need luck, I have you!
他们这是干嘛?
What are they doing?
如果卡西安回来 我们会不等他们就离开
If Cassian comes back, we're leaving without them.
你看见厄索从那儿出来?
You see Erso out there?
我们已经走了很远
We've come too far.
耐心 我的朋友
Patience, my friend.
那是他
That's him.
那是他 盖伦 穿黑衣那个
That's him, Galen, in the dark suit.
回到下面去 帮我们找个飞船离开这儿
Get back down there, and find us a ride out of here.
你要做什么?
What are you doing?
你听过了你说我们爬上来只是看看
You heard me. You said we came up here just to have a look
我在这里 我在看走
I'm here, I'm looking. Go.
快点!
Hurry!
绝好消息 盖伦战斗空间站完成
Excellent news, Galen. The battle station is complete.
你一定很自豪
You must be very proud.
尽量自豪 克伦尼克
Proud as I can be, Krennic.
召集你的工程师 我有一个公告
Gather your engineers, I have an announcement.
他们都在这儿?是的
Is that all of them? Yes.
先生们
Gentlemen.
你们中有人背叛了帝国
One of you betrayed the Empire.
你们中有人与飞行员密谋送消息给反抗军
One of you has conspired with a pilot to send messages to the Rebellion.
我敦促那叛徒向前迈上一步
And I urge that traitor step forward.
非常好 那么我就当这是一个团队的杰作
Very well, I'll consider it a group effort, then.
准备!别别 拜托
Ready!No. No, please.
瞄准…
Aim. . .
继续…不 不
and…No, no.
开火!住手!住手!克伦尼克 住手是我干的
fire! Stop! Stop! Krennic, stop. It was me.
是我干的
It was me.
他们与此无关饶了他们
They have nothing to do with it. Spare them.
开火!
Fire!
我怎么知道武器已完工?
How do I know the weapon is complete?
让我给你分享些细节…
Let me share with you some details. .
卡西安
Cassian.
卡西安 你听得到我吗?
Cassian, can you hear me?
我在这儿你使它起作用了
I'm here. You got it working.
肯定是的 虽然我们有个问题!
Affirmative yes, although we have a problem!
联盟中队正在逼近
There's an Alliance squadron approaching.
清剿此区!不不 不 不!
Clear the area!No. No, no, no!
叫他们暂缓 琴还在平台上!
Tell them to hold up!Jyn's on that platform!
杰达
Jedha.
索·格雷拉他那些狂热分子的队伍
Saw Gerrera. His band of fanatics.
他们的圣城绝地的最后记忆没了
Their Holy City. The last reminder of the Jedi. Gone.
你毫无胜算
You'll never win.
此前我是在哪里听过这话?
Now where have I heard that before?
转发自安多上尉
Relay from Captain Andor.
将军安多上尉请求延迟中队支援
General. Captain Andor requesting a delay on squadron support.
联盟部队总部 请确认
Alliance forces onsite. Please confirm.
联络中队队长 立即联络他!
Get the squadron leader on, Get him on now!
他们已占线 长官
They're already engaged, sir.
死了?
Dead
不
No.
还击!去你的岗位
Return fire!To your stations.
让我们的战机升空!马上!
Get our fighters in the air now!
父亲!
Father!
走 走 走 走后退!后退!
Go, go, go, go. Fall back! Fall back!
主管 我们必须撤离
Director, we need to evacuate.
爸爸爸爸 是我啊
Papa. Papa, it's me.
我是琴
It's Jyn.
琴
Jyn.
星尘
Stardust.
爸爸
Papa.
我看到你的消息了
I've seen your message.
全息影像 我看到它了
The hologram, I've seen it.
死星必须被摧毁
It must be destroyed
我知我知
I know. I know.
我们会去
We will.
琴
Jyn.
看看你
Look at you.
我有太多话要告诉你
I've so much to tell you.
爸爸
Papa.
不不…
No. No…
爸爸…爸爸!拜托
Papa…Papa!Come on.
在那边 干掉他们
Over there, take them down.
拜托
Come on.
琴 我们必须走了快点我不能丢下他
Jyn, we've got to go. Come on. I can't leave him,
听我说他走了
Listen to me. He's gone.
你无能无力来吧
There's nothing you can do. Come on.
我不能丢下他快点!
I can't leave him. Come on!
帮帮我走吧!
Help me. Move!
伏下!
Down!
快点快点
Come on. Come on.
干得好你现在是反叛者了
Well done. You're a Rebel now.
我们走 我们走快点 我们离开!
Let's go, let's go. Come on, let's move!
快点 让我们离开这儿
Come on, let's get out of here.
行动 行动 行动
Move, move, move.
好了 克图 我们走
Okay, K-2, let's go.
收到
Copy that.
离子推进器低耗直到我们离开风暴明白
Ion thrusters low until we cleared the storm. Understood.
你欺骗我
You lied to me.
你骇着了
You're in shock.
你去那儿是要杀死我父亲
You went up there to kill my father.
你不知道自己在说什么
You don't know what you're talking about.
承认吧!
Deny it!
你骇着了 想找个地方减压
You're in shock, and looking for someplace to put it.
我以前看到过我打赌你有
I've seen it before. I bet you have.
他们知道
They know.
你撒谎为什么我们来这里还撒谎为什么你要独自上去
You lied about why we came here and you lied about why you went up alone.
我有每一个机会扣扳机 但我有吗?
I had every chance to pull the trigger. But did I?
我有吗?
Did I?
你可能是有
You might as well have.
我父亲是活生生的证据 你却拿他冒险
My father was living proof and you put him at risk.
是联盟的炸弹杀死了他!
Those were Alliance bombs that killed him!
我是有命令!我没服从的命令!
I had orders!Orders that I disobeyed!
但是你不会明白命令?
But you wouldn't understand that. Orders?
当你知道他们错了?
When you know they're wrong?
你还不如当一个暴风兵
You might as well be a stormtrooper.
你又懂什么?
What do you know?
决定何时何地我们应当关心何事的奢望 我们都没有
We don't all have the luxury of deciding when and where we want to care about something.
你突然当反抗军是真的?
Suddenly the Rebellion is real for you?
我们中有人活在其中
Some of us live it.
我6岁大就参与战斗了
I've been in this fight since I was 6 years old.
你并不是唯一的失去了一切的人
You're not the only one who lost everything.
我们中有人决定为此做点事
Some of us just decided to do something about it.
你不必这样谈论你的方式
You can't talk your way around this.
是没必要
I don't have to.
雅文四!
Yavin Four!
确保他们知道我们是用偷的飞船进港
Make sure they know we're coming in with a stolen ship.
谁还有事?
Anybody else?
穆斯塔法
MUSTAFAR
尊敬的阁下 主管克伦尼克已到
My lord, Director Krennic has arrived.
主管克伦尼克
Director Krennic.
勋爵维达
Lord Vader.
你看似不安
You seem unsettled.
不 只是时间紧迫
No. Just pressed for time.
有很多事情要处理
There're a great many things to attend to.
我道歉
My apologies.
你确有很多事情需要解释
You do have a great many things to explain.
我已经交付了皇帝要求的武器
I've delivered the weapon the Emperor requested
我应得到一个观众以确保他明白它非凡的潜力
I deserve an audience to make certain he understands its remarkable potential.
它的力量足以制造各种问题肯定已得到了证实
Its power to create problems has certainly been confirmed.
一座城市被摧毁
A city destroyed.
一个帝国设施的公开攻击
An Imperial facility openly attacked.
这是总督塔金建议的测试
It was Governor Tarkin that suggested the test.
你不是被招唤于此卑躬屈膝 主管克伦尼克
You were not summoned here to grovel, Director Krennic.
不 我…这里没有死星
No, I…There is no Death Star.
参议院已被告知 杰达在采矿灾害中被摧毁了
The Senate has been informed that Jedha was destroyed in a mining disaster.
是的 尊敬的阁下
Yes, my lord.
我希望你不要休息 直到你能向皇帝保证
I expect you to not rest until you can assure the Emperor
盖伦·厄索没有以任何方式损害武器
that Galen Erso has not compromised this weapon in any way.
所以我仍然在指挥?
So I'm still in command?
你会跟皇帝谈谈—
You'Ll speak to the Emperor about—
小心不要被你的愿望们窒息 主管
Be careful not to choke on your aspirations, Director.
我们必须分散舰队
We must scatter the fleet.
我们没有依靠只能投降
We have no recourse but to surrender.
我们真的是在谈论解散我们辛辛苦苦创建的东西吗?
Are we really talking about disbanding something that we've worked so hard to create?
我们不能只是屈服我们加入了一个联盟 而不是一个自杀协议!
We can't just give in. We joined an Alliance, not a suicide pact!
我们现在才设法集结我们的部队集结我们的部队?
We've only now managed to gather our forces. Gather our forces?
德雷文将军已经炸毁一个帝国空间站!
General Draven's already blown up an Imperial base!
需要制定一个对策
A decision needed to be made.
如果这是你想要的战争 你将独自战斗!
If it's war you want, you'll fight alone!
如果那是大势所趋 为什么一直要有一个联盟?
If that's the way it's going, why have an Alliance at all?
如果她说的是真的 我们需要立即行动!
If she's telling the truth, we need to act now!
委员 有请!
Councilors, please!
很简单 帝国有大规模杀伤性手段反抗军没有
It is simple, the Empire has the means of mass destruction. The Rebellion does not.
死星 这是胡说
A Death Star, this is nonsense.
什么原因使我父亲非得说谎?这能带给他什么好处?
What reason would my father have to lie? What benefit would it bring him?
引诱我们的部队进入一场最终战役 一劳永逸摧毁我们
To lure our forces into a final battle. To destroy us once and for all.
要冒一切风险 基于什么? 一个罪犯的证词?
To risk everything, based on what? The testimony of a criminal?
她父亲的临终遗言 一位帝国科学家?
The dying words of her father, an Imperial scientist?
别忘了帝国飞行员
Don't forget the Imperial pilot.
我父亲献出了自己的生命 这样我们就有机会战胜这些
My father gave his life so that we may have a chance to defeat this.
那你告诉我们
So you've told us.
如果帝国有这种力量 我们又有什么机会?
If the Empire has this kind of power, what chance do we have?
我们又有什么机会?
What chance do we have?
问题是"什么选择?"
The question is 'What choice?'
跑?隐藏?恳求宽恕?分散你们的部队?
Run? Hide? Plead for mercy? Scatter your forces?
你让路给这个具有如此力量的邪恶的敌人
You give way to an enemy this evil with this much power
你再宣判银河系要永恒的屈服
and you condemn the galaxy to an eternity of submission.
战斗的时刻就是现在!是的
The time to fight is now!Yes.
每一刻你浪费的 不过是又一步距杰达的灰烬更近
Every moment you waste is another step closer to the ashes of Jedha.
她有什么建议?且让那女孩说说!
What is she proposing? Just let the girl speak!
派你最好的军队去斯卡里夫
Send your best troops to Scarif.
派出整个反抗军舰队如果你不得不
Send the whole rebel fleet if you have to.
我们需要夺取死星蓝图只要有任何希望能摧毁它
We need to capture the Death Star plans if there is any hope of destroying it.
你在要求我们入侵一个帝国的基地 基于的却只有希望?
You're asking us to invade an Imperial installation based on nothing but hope?
反抗建立于希望
Rebellions are built on hope.
没希望了
There is no hope.
我说我们得战斗
I say we fight.
我说反抗军是结束了
I say the Rebellion is finished.
我很抱歉 琴
I'm sorry, Jyn.
没有委员会的全力支持,
Without the full support of the council,
赔率太大
the odds are too great.
将军本多拉 请向简报室报告
General Bendola, please report to the briefing room.
你看起来不高兴
You don't look happy.
他们宁愿投降你呢?
They prefer to surrender. And you?
她想战斗我也想我们都想
She wants to fight. So do I. We all do.
她的原力很强大
The Force is strong.
我不能确定我们四人已是足够
I'm not sure four of us is quite enough.
我们需要多少人?你又在说啥呢?
How many do we need? What are you talking about?
他们永远不会相信你
They were never going to believe you.
我感谢大家的支持
I appreciate the support.
但是我信
But I do.
我相信你
I believe you.
我们乐当志愿者
We'd like to volunteer
我们中有人…
Some of us. . .
…我们中的大多数
…most of us,
我们做过可怕的事只为支持反抗军
we've done terrible things on behalf of the Rebellion.
我们是间谍破坏者杀手
We're spies. Saboteurs. Assassins.
我做过的每件事
Everything I did,
都是为反抗军做的
I did for the Rebellion.
每一次我从我想忘记的事情中走开
And every time I walked away from something I wanted to forget
我告诉自己这是为了一个我相信的事业
I told myself it was for a cause that I believed in.
一个值得的事业
A cause that was worth it.
不这样想 我们就会迷失
Without that, we're lost.
我们所做的一切都将失去意义
Everything we've done would have been for nothing.
我无法面对自己如果现在我放弃
I couldn't face myself if I gave up now.
我们没有一个人能面对
None of us could.
飞船不会舒适
It won'T be comfortable.
会有些拥挤 但我们都能习惯
It'll be a bit cramped, but we'll all fit.
我们可以去
We could go.
好了准备行动
Okay. Gear up.
带上所有没有被钉住的东西
Grab anything that's not nailed down.
快 快 快!
Go, go, go!
琴
Jyn.
我会为你去哪儿
I'll be there for you.
卡西安说我必须去
Cassian said I had to.
我可不习惯人们在事情变坏时四处逗留
I'm not used to people sticking around when things go bad
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
亡命徒小队到情报处提交任务报告
Bravo team to the Intelligence office for extraction mission report.
愿原力与我们同在
May the Force be with us.
货运穿梭机 回复 拜托
Cargo shuttle, read back, please.
你那边是怎么回事?
What's going on out there?
那船禁飞任何人都不应该在船上 直到进一步指示
That ship's off limits. No one is suppose to be on board until farther instructions.
是的 是的 我们是肯定
Yes, yes we are. Affirmative.
那是艘被扣押的帝国飞船你的代号是什么?飞行员?
That's an impounded Imperial ship. What's your call sign, pilot?
嗯我们必须走了
Um. We have to go.
这-这是 嗯…
It-It's um. . .
说点啥 快点
Say something. Come on.
侠盗…
Rogue. . .
侠盗一号
Rogue One.
侠盗一号?没有侠盗一号
Rogue One? There is no Rogue One.
好吧 现在有了
Well, there is now.
侠盗一号 启动启动
Rogue One, pulling away. Pulling away.
不管别人怎么说 战争难免
Despite what the others say, war is inevitable
是的 我同意我必须回到奥德朗
Yes, I agree. I must return to Alderaan
通知我的人民将不会有和平
to inform my people that there will be no peace.
我们将需要每一个先机
We will need every advantage.
你的朋友 绝地武士
Your friend, the Jedi.
他在克隆人战争期间很好的辅助过我
He served me well during the Clone Wars
自从皇帝大清洗以来就一直躲藏着
and has lived in hiding since the Emperor's purge.
会的 我会派人找他
Yes, I will send for him.
你会需要一个你能信任的人
You'll need someone you can trust.
我能用我的生命去信任她
I would trust her with my life.
队长安的列斯 我有任务给你参议员
Captain Antilles, I have a mission for you. Senator.
斯卡里夫 帝国综合安全
SCARIF IMPERIAL SECURITY COMPLEX
好了 我们来了
Okay, we're coming in.
这里有一个全球防御护盾仅有一个主要的出入门
There's a planetwide defensive shield with a single main entry gate.
这艘飞船应该配备一个接入码以让我们通过
This shuttle should be equipped with an access code that allows us through.
假设 帝国还没有登录它作为逾期
Assuming, the Empire hasn't logged it as overdue.
但要是他们有呢?
And if they have?
那 他们关上了门 我们都被消灭在寒冷 黑暗的真空宇宙
Then, they shut the gate and we're all annihilated in the cold, dark vacuum of space.
我不会
Not me,
我能生存在太空中
I can survive in space.
好了我要说了
Okay. Here it goes…
货运飞船Sw-0608请求停机坪
Cargo shuttle SW-0608 requesting a landing pad.
货运飞船Sw-0608 您未列出在抵达清单上
Cargo shuttle SW-0608, you're not listed on the arrival schedule.
确认 大门控制中心
Acknowledged, Gate Control.
我们绕道自伊杜飞行空间站
We were rerouted from Eadu Flight Station.
立刻发送清除代码发送
Transmitting clearance code now. Transmitting.
货运飞船Sw-0608?
Cargo shuttle SW-0608?
您已清零以进入好极!
You are cleared for entry. Yes!
了不起
Impressive.
我要告诉其他人
I'll tell the others.
好的
Okay.
SW-0608 确定停机坪9确认 谢谢
SW-0608 clear for landing pad 9. Acknowledge, please.
SW-0608 按照指示行至9号台
SW-0608 proceeding to LP9 as instructed.
主建筑在那下面 那是什么?
The main building down there, what is it?
那是堡垒之塔他们把所有的帝国构造档案放那里
That's the Citadel Tower. They keep all the Imperial structure archives in there.
如果蓝图在某处 它们会在那儿
If the plans are anywhere, they'll be there.
顶部那个碟形?它有什么用?
The dish at the top? What's it for?
我想它收集大量的信号向外发送那些数据文件
I guess it takes a lot of signals to send those data files out.
着陆轨迹已衔接
Landing track engaged
着陆轨迹已锁定
Landing track locked.
我们已着陆
We're landing.
我们进来了!
We're coming in!
索·格雷拉常说 一个有着锋利棍子的战士
Saw Gerrera used to say, One fighter with a sharp stick
没有什么可以失去 就能赢得胜利
and nothing left to lose can take the day.
他们不知道我们进来了
They have no idea we're coming.
他们没有理由预料我们
They have no reason to expect us.
如果我们能成功 我们将抓住下一次机会
If we can make it to the ground, we'll take the next chance.
接着下一个一个又一个直到我们赢…
And the next. On and on until we win. . .
否则这些机会失效
or the chances are spent.
死星蓝图就在那里
The Death Star plans are down there.
卡西安 克图 和我会找到它
Cassian, Kay-Tu, and I will find them.
我们会找到办法以找到它
We'll find a way to find them.
墨尔西, 帕奥, 贝兹 奇鲁 你们率领主力
Melshi, Pao, Baze, Chirrut, you'll take main squad,
向东移动并占领飞船周围更大范围
move east and get wide of the ship.
在这里和塔之间找到一个位置
Find a position between here and the tower.
一旦你到达最佳地点 引爆那地方
Once you get to the best spot, light the place up.
让十个人感觉像一百好的
Make ten men feel like a hundred. All right.
让那些守兵不能靠近我们
And get those troopers away from us.
我应该做什么?
What should I do?
保持引擎运转 你是我们离开这儿的唯一方法
Keep the engine running. You're our only way out of here.
货运穿梭机Sw-0608 准备接受检查小组
Cargo shuttle SW-0608, be prepared to receive inspection team.
准备?
Ready?
你好
Hello.
嘿 你可能在寻找一个清单…
Hey, You'Re probably looking for a manifest…
那会很有用
That would be helpful.
它就在这下面
It's just down here.
主管克伦尼克 我们正进入斯卡里夫护盾门
Director Krennic, we are entering the Scarif shield gate.
将军Ramda已被告知您的到来
General Ramda has been informed of your arrival.
祝好运 小妹妹
Good luck, little sister.
走!快走 你没事了!
Go!Go now, you're clear!
好吧 我们走快走行动 行动 行动
All right, let's go. Come on. Move, move, move.
我有个不好的感觉—
I have a bad feeling about—
克!安静
Kay!Quiet.
什么?
What?
我们需要地图
We need a map.
好吧 我敢肯定有一个刚好闲置
Well, I'm sure there's one just lying about.
你知道你要做什么
You know what you have to do.
每机坪一个选择你的位置 我们要他们吸引过来
One per pad. Pick your spot. We want to draw them out.
我会适时呼叫走!
I'll call the timing. Go!
嘿 你听到谣言了吗?
Hey, did you hear the rumors?
是的 这T-15S已标记为过时
Yeah, the T-15s have been marked obsolete.
哦 男孩 那是关于那事的时间
Oh boy, it's about time for that.
嘿小心
Hey. Watch out.
什么 那…?
What the…?
主管 什么风把你吹来了?
Director, what brings you to Scarif?
盖伦·厄索 我要他曾派发的每一次调度 每一次传送 全部都要检查
Galen Erso, I want every dispatch, every transmission he has ever sent called up for inspection.
所有的?
All of them?
是的 所有的
Yes. All of them.
马上开始
Get started.
克?
Kay?
我们到数据库的最佳路线 沿途只有89个暴风兵值守
Our optimal route to the data vault places only 89 stormtroopers in our path.
在我们被杀前我们要避免挡道的超过33%
We will make it no more than 33% of the way before we are killed.
墨尔西 回话
Melshi, talk to me.
准备 准备 待命
Ready, ready. Standing by.
点燃它!
Light it up.
我们瞎了吗?部署驻军!行动!
Are we blind? Deploy the garrison! Move!
突击队!
Troopers!
突击队 左侧有突击队!
Troopers. Troopers on the left!
长官?斯卡里夫基地 他们报告反抗军入侵
Sir? Scarif base, they're reporting a rebel incursion.
我要跟主管克伦尼克通话
I want to speak to Director Krennic.
他在那里 长官在斯卡里夫
He's there, sir. On Scarif.
这个空间站的原始蓝图保存在那里 不是吗?
The original plans for this station are kept there, are they not?
在那里
They are.
准备进入超空间并通知勋爵维达
Prepare for the jump to hyperspace and inform Lord Vader.
要我帮你吗?
Can I help you?
无此必要
That won't be necessary.
委员!
Senator!
委员
Senator.
站在那儿 二等兵
Stop right there, Private.
让他说吧
Let him speak.
截获帝国信息 女士斯卡里夫有反抗
Intercepted Imperial transmission, ma'am. Rebels on Scarif.
我要找上将拉杜斯
I need to speak to Admiral Raddus.
他已返回他的战舰 他去战斗了
He's returned to his ship He's gone to fight.
不!
No!
所有飞行人员注意 请立即向指挥官报告
Attention all flight personnel, please report to your commanders immediately.
我们被重定向到斯卡里夫
We have been redirected to Scarif.
飞行员们 你们将在途中向你们的中队领导人汇报
Pilots, you'll be briefed by you squadron leaders on route.
愿原力与你同在
May the Force be with you.
斯卡里夫?他们这是去斯卡里夫?
Scarif? They're going to Scarif?
为何没人告诉过我任何事 阿图…? 是啊 没人告诉我们任何事
Why does nobody ever tell me anything, Artoo…?Yeah, Nobody tells us anything.
撤退!撤退!
Fall back! Fall back!
继续吸引他们过来!
Keep drawing them out!
走走行动行动
Go. Go. Move. Move.
快点 动起来!
Come on, move up!
机坪12汇报阵地在我们侧翼 我们寡不敌众.
Pad 12 report to ground. Coming at our flank, we're outnumbered.
机坪12小队 那边出了什么事?现状 谢谢
Pad 12 team, what's going on down there. Status, please.
所有机坪立即汇报
All Pads report in immediately.
不知 我们到处都有反抗军
Unknown, we have rebels everywhere.
我们正在交战 机坪12 机坪14要求增援
We're taking fire, Pad 12, Pad 14 request assistance.
这是机坪2 机坪2我发现40个反抗军由机坪2向西前进
This is Pad 2, Pad 2. I spot 40 rebels heading west on Pad 2.
联络那边 告诉他机坪5被反抗军牵制了
Get on there, tell him pinned down by rebels on Pad 5.
这是机坪5 我们正在被占领救救我们!
This is Pad 5, we're being overrun. Help us!
机坪12 机坪10 机坪8 请确认确认后汇报
Pad 12, Pad 10, Pad 8, please confirm. Confirm and report.
立即让增援部队去机坪5
Get reinforcements down to Pad 5 immediately!
这样不管用 克
This is not working, Kay.
右手
Right hand.
贝兹!
Baze!
贝兹!干啥?
Baze! What?
跑!
Run!
撤退撤退
Retreat. Retreat!
这是反抗军联盟上将拉杜斯所有中队队长报告
This is Admiral Raddus of the Rebel Alliance. All Squadron leaders report in.
上将 这是蓝色队长待命中
Admiral, this is Blue Leader standing by.
这是金色队长 待命中
This is Gold Leader, standing by.
这是红色队长 待命中
This is Red Leader, standing by.
长官 那些是反抗军战舰
Sir, those are rebel ships.
联系上将戈林 立即
Get Admiral Gorin, immediately.
主管 反抗军舰队 正在护盾外侧聚集
Director, the rebel fleet, it's amassing outside the shield.
锁上基地锁上
Lock down the base. Lock down.
关闭护盾?关闭!
And close the shield? Do it!
红色和金色中队 攻击阵型 保卫舰队
Red and Gold squadron, attack formations. Defend the fleet.
蓝色中队 在他们关闭那扇大门前抵达地面
Blue squadron, get to the surface before they closed that gate.
收到 上将阁下
Copy, your Admiral.
蓝色中队 掩护
Blue squadron, on me.
收到 蓝色队长收到 蓝色队长
Copy, Blue Leader. Copy, Blue Leader.
我们不用太久
We won't have long.
关上护盾关上它!
Close the field. Close it!
快点 快点 快点!
Come on, come on, come on!
拉起来!
Pull up!
反抗军舰队已经抵达什么?
Rebel fleet has arrived. What?
海滩上有战斗
There's fighting on the beach,
他们已锁上基地
they've locked down the base,
他们已经关上护盾门那意味着啥?
they've closed the shield gate. What does that mean?
我们被困住了?
We're trapped?
我们可以把蓝图传送给反抗军舰队
We could transmit the plans to the rebel fleet.
我们必须让信号发出以告知他们它来了
We'd have to get a signal out to tell them it's coming.
数据文件的大小会是问题所在
It's the size of the data files. That's the problem.
它们永远不能通过
They'll never get through.
必须有人把护盾门干掉
Someone has to take that shield gate down.
菩提菩提 你能听见吗?
Bodhi. Bodhi, can you hear me?
菩提 告诉我你在那边
Bodhi, tell me you're out there.
菩提!
Bodhi!
你好 我在这儿我们正在待命
Hello, I'm here. We're standing by.
他们已经开始战斗 基地被关闭了!
They've started fighting, the base is on lockdown!
我知 听我说!反抗军舰队就在那上边
I know, listen to me! The rebel fleet is up there.
你得告诉他们在护盾门上炸个洞
You've got to tell them to blow a hole in the shield gate
这样我们才能传送蓝图
so we can transmit the plans.
等下 我不能 我不能连接到通讯塔我们没有绑在一起
Wait, I can't. I'm not hooked into the comm tower. We're not tied in.
这是唯一的办法把数据从这儿传出去
It's the only way we're getting them out of here.
找到办法!守住我们后方
Find a way!Cover our backs.
你需要这个
You'll need this.
你想要一个 对吗?
You wanted one, right?
你的行为 琴·厄索 总是意外连连
Your behavior, Jyn Erso, is continually unexpected.
琴快来
Jyn. Come on.
按我命令开火
Fire on my command.
看啦!
Look!
准备好我们将要到那外面去
Get ready. We're going to have to go out there.
你要做什么?
What're you doing?
他们关闭了护盾门 我们困在这儿了
They closed the shield gate, we're stuck here.
但是 反抗军舰队进来了
But, the rebel fleet is pulling in.
我们只需要得到一个足够强大的信号以接通他们
We just have to get a signal strong enough to get through to them
并让他们知道我们陷入困境
and let them know we're trapped down here.
为此 我们必须连接到通信塔
For that, we have to connect to the communications tower.
现在 我可以就在这儿给我们打补丁 停机坪
Now, I can patch us in over here, the landing pad
但你必须用无线电 叫一个外边的伙计去找
but you have to get on the radio, get one of the guys out there to find
一个主开关
a master switch.
让他们来激活我们跟通讯塔之间的连接 好了
Get them to activate the connection between us and that comm tower. Okay.
那就走!
Then go!
下面情况如何 中尉?
What's going on down there, Lieutenant?
未知 长官我们不能集结他们
Unknown, sir. We can't raise them.
所有反抗军频率被封锁
All rebel frequencies are blocked.
继续尝试衔接那些星际驱逐舰让我们攻击那个护盾
Keep trying. Engage those Star Destroyers and let's start probing that shield.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
我们要进去了
We're going in.
跟我呆一块儿
Stay with me.
原理图银行 数据塔二号
Schematics bank, Data tower two.
我怎么找到它?搜索
How do I find that? Searching.
我能找到磁带 但你需要手柄去提取
I can locate the tape, but you'll need the handles for extraction.
我们应该怎样做呢用这些?
What are we supposed to do with these?
喔
Whoa.
好了 终于等下 停止
Well, finally. Wait, stop.
反抗军!他们去…在那边
The rebels}!They went…Over there.
克那边怎么回事儿?
Kay. What's going on out there?
这家伙
There's one.
噢 好吧
Oh well.
来吧!
Come on!
红色队长 这是金色队长
Red Leader, this is Gold Leader,
我们正开始继续攻击屏蔽门
we're starting our attack run on the shield gate.
保持紧凑并提防那些炮塔
Keep it tight and watch out for those towers.
更多钛战机编队 位于65
More fighters. Form up, at 65.
长官 敌军钛战机来了
Sir, enemy fighters coming in.
墨尔西墨尔西 回答 你在那儿吗?
Melshi. Melshi, come in, are you there?
菩提将从这里发出一个信号他在给我们打补丁
Bodhi will send a signal from here. He's patching us in.
但是你们必须为塔打开一条线
But you guys have to open up a line for the tower.
怎么弄?请告知
How? Please advise.
有个主开关在通讯塔基部
There's a master switch to the base of the Comm tower.
主开关 描述 我们要找啥?
Master switch, describe, what are we looking for?
看起来象啥?主开关?它在哪儿?
What does it look like, the master switch? Where is it?
双翼 增援海滩上的中队
Two wings, reinforce those troops on the beach.
所有战机 掩护我们必须保护他们免受空中攻击
All fighters, on me. We have to shield them from air attack.
部队增援 我们去吧
Troop reinforcements. Here we go.
为杰达!杰达!
For Jedha!Jedha!
我们对那个护盾没有影响
We have no effect on that shield.
那东西被打掉还要多久?
How much more can that thing take?
跟紧点 红色5 你去哪儿?
Stick close, Red 5, where are you going?
我试图摆脱他们
I'm trying to lose them.
这是红色5 我需要帮助!
This is Red 5, I need help!
超空间跟踪
Hyperspace Tracking,
导航系统
Navigational Systems.
双屏幕下结构工程 打开那个!
Two screens down. Structural Engineering, open that one!
有个敌机在我的尾巴上
I got one on my tail.
我能搞定
I'm on it.
项目代号：恒星球标记欧米茄帕克斯极光…
Project code names:Stellarsphere. Mark Omega. Pax Aurora…
战斗-斗篷克拉斯特-棱镜黑色-光剑
War-Mantle. Cluster-Prism. Black-Saber.
什么?
What?
星尘
Stardust.
就是它
That's it.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know that?
我知因为那是我
I know because it's me.
嘿 你自报身份
Hey, you. Identify yourself.
我可以解释
I can explain.
炮火 找掩护!
Incoming fire, take cover!
克 我们需要星尘的文件!
Kay, we need the file for Stardust!
星尘
Stardust.
就是它
That's it.
克
Kay.
爬上去
Climb.
你仍然能发送蓝图给舰队
You can still send the plans to the fleet.
如果他们打开护盾门 你可以从塔上传播!
If they open the shield gate, you can broadcast from the tower!
现在锁上螺栓门克
Locking the bolt door now. Kay.
克!
Kay!
再见克!
Good bye. Kay!
长官 数据库有未经授权的访问
Sir, unauthorized access at the data vault.
什么它只是进入 长官
What. It's just come in, sir.
派我的警卫中队上阵!两人马上跟我走!
Send my guard squadron into battle! Two men with me now!
把那个海滩置于控制下!
Get that beach under control!
菩提?你在吗?
Bodhi? Are you there?
你拿到开关了?
Have you got the switch?
我不能上穿梭机 我没法插上!
I can't get to the shuttle, I can't plug in!
你得上!他们得炸开那门
You have to! They have to hit that gate.
如果护盾打开 我们就能发送蓝图!
If the shield's open, we can send the plans!
将军 你后面!
General, behind you!
赶他们出去
Take them out.
退后
Step back.
我们要坠机了!
We're going down!
来吧!
Come on!
当心
Look out.
墨尔西墨尔西请回答
Melshi. Melshi, come in please.
我困在最后一步 我只需一条开放线路
I'm tied in at my end, I just need an open line.
稍等
Hang on.
那个主开关 就在那个控制台那边
The master switch, it's over at that console.
我要去!
I'm going!
我拿到它了
I've got it.
小心!
Careful!
你还好?
You okay?
琴!
Jyn!
我与原力同在 原力与我同在
I'm one with the Force and the Force is with me.
奇鲁!
Chirrut!
我与原力同在 原力与我同在
I'm one with the Force and the Force is with me.
奇鲁 回来!
Chirrut, come back!
好极!
Yes!
继续继续!
Keep going. Keep going!
卡西安
Cassian.
奇鲁 来!跟我来!
Chirrut, come!Come with me!
奇鲁!
Chirrut!
奇鲁 不要走不要走
Chirrut, don't go. Don't go.
我在这儿我在这儿
I'm here. I'm here.
没事的没事的
It's okay. It's okay.
寻找原力 奇鲁
Look for the Force, Chirrut.
你总能找到我
and you will always find me.
原力与我同在
The Force is with me.
我与原力同在
I'm one with the Force.
原力与我同在
The Force is with me.
我与原力同在
I'm one with the Force.
原力与我同在
The Force is with me.
我与原力同在
and I'm one with the Force.
偏导盾下降至于50% 我们正承受严重破坏
Deflector shield's down to 50%, we're sustaining heavy damage.
现在没有回头路了 我们得竭力进攻
There's no turning back now, we have to press the attack.
打击那个炸开的
Hit that opening.
我们看见了 金色队长
We see it, Gold Leader.
离子鱼雷发射
Ion torpedoes away.
出什么事了?我们已失去引擎动力 长官
What's happening? We've lost engine power, sir.
那个星际驱逐舰被废了
That Star Destroyer is disabled.
这是侠盗一号 呼叫任何能听见我的联盟飞船!
This is Rogue One, calling any Alliance ships that can hear me!
有没有人在上边?这是侠盗一号!回答 完毕
Is there anybody up there? This is Rogue One! Come in, over.
这是上将拉杜斯 侠盗一号 我们听到你了!
This is Admiral Raddus, Rogue One, we hear you!
我们拿到蓝图!
We have the plans!
他们已找到死星蓝图他们必须从通讯塔传送它们!
They found the Death Star plans. They have to transmit them from the communications tower!
你必须拿下护盾门那是唯一的办法可以将它们通过!
You have to take down the shield gate. It's the only way to going to get them through!
调出锤头轻型护卫舰我有一个想法
Call up a Hammerhead corvette. I have an idea.
待命 侠盗一号 我们正在弄这是为了你 盖伦
Standby, Rogue One, we're on it. This is for you, Galen,
原力与我同在我与原力同在
The Force is with me. I'm one with the Force.
护卫舰5 锁定目标
Corvette 5, locked on target.
准备碰撞
Prepare for impact.
亚光速推进器 全功率!
Sublight thrusters, full power!
重置天线对准
Reset antenna alignment.
反向发动机 全功率!
Reverse engines, full power!
天线对准. 准备传送
Antenna alignment. Ready to transmit.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你知我是谁
You know who I am.
我是琴·厄索
I'm Jyn Erso.
盖伦和莱拉之女
Daughter of Galen and Lyra.
你已输了
You've lost.
噢 我输了 有吗?
Oh, I have, have I?
我父亲的复仇他建造了一个缺陷在死星里
My father's revenge. He built a flaw in the Death Star.
他放入了一根导火索在你的机器中间
He put a fuse in the middle of your machine
而我只是告诉整个星系如何点燃它
and I've just told the entire galaxy how to light it.
护盾在上面 你的信号永远不会到达反抗军基地
The shield is up, your signal will never reach the rebel base.
你们在这里的所有飞船都会被摧毁
All you ships in here will be destroyed.
我没输掉任何东西除了时间
I lose nothing but time.
你 另一方面 与反抗军同死
YOU on the other hand die with the Rebellion.
传送中
Transmitting.
上将 收到来自斯卡里夫的信息
Admiral, receiving transmission from Scarif.
嘿 别管了别管了
Hey, leave it. Leave it.
就这样
That's it.
我们走
Let's go.
信息已收
Transmission received.
上将 我们得到蓝图!
Admiral, we have the plans!
她成功了
She did it.
你觉得有没有人在听着?
Do you think, anybody is listening?
我有
I do.
有人在那边
Someone's out there.
长官 我们检测到一个巨大的物体自超空间出现
Sir, we're detecting a massive object emerging from hyperspace.
长官 要我开始瞄准他们的舰队吗?
Sir, shall I begin targeting their fleet?
勋爵维达会操控住舰队
Lord Vader will handle the fleet.
瞄准斯卡里夫的基地单反应堆点火
Target the base at Scarif. Single reactor ignition
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
准备好就开火.
You may fire when ready.
开始初级点火
Commence primary ignition.
侠盗一号 愿原力与你同在
Rogue One, may the Force be with you.
所有飞船 准备进入超空间!
All ships, prepare for jump to hyperspace!
你父亲会以你为荣 琴
You father would have been proud of you, Jyn.
反抗军旗舰已被废 尊敬的阁下
The rebel flag ship is disabled, my lord
但是已经收到来自地面的信息
but has received transmission from the surface.
准备强行登舰
Prepare a boarding party.
遵命 尊敬的阁下
Yes, my lord.
快点!
Hurry!
撤!我们现在必须走
Let go! We got to go now.
快点 我们走
Hurry, let's go.
它被卡住了
It's stuck.
嘿 救命!
Hey, help!
开火!
Open fire!
救救我们!
Help us!
它被堵塞了
It's jammed.
推!
Push!
这儿这儿拿去!拿去!
Here. Here. Take it! Take it.
发动!
LAUNCH!
确保你锁紧空气锁准备逃生舱
Make sure you secure the airlock. And prepare the escape pods.
殿下我们已收到信息
Your Highness. The transmission we received.
他们送给我们的是什么?
What is it they've sent us?
希望
Hope.